Stay where you are and put
your hands in the air.
My safe.
Did you open my safe?
Stop!
Hands behind your back.
- On your feet now.
- Get up.
Come on.
Thanks.
Just a couple bucks, buddy.
Help a guy out.
Just need to know if you saw
anything, sir, anything at all.
I don't know.
Maybe if you tell me
what you're looking for
I could help you out.
I don't know.
Loud noise, gunshot.
Did you see anyone unusual?
Anyone acting unusually?
Maybe I did.
Or...
Or maybe I didn't.
You give me a couple bucks
maybe help me remember better.
- You got 2 bucks?
- No. You?
Looks like a robbery gone bad.
Victim's name was Ted Fisher.
He owned the place.
Something's off here.
The alarm was set off during the break-in
and the killer still took the time
to tear the place apart?
Watch the blood. Rug's pretty soaked.
And if the killer
broke the door entering
why is the victim over here
with his back turned?
- Something's off here.
- That's very astute, Lisbon.
- There's more here than meets the eye.
- There you are. Where have you been?
I haven't been anywhere.
I was out back checking escape routes.
Really? Any clues?
Only that the murderer didn't find
what he was looking for.
And... how do you know that?
Because this whole room
has been torn apart.
You find what you're looking for,
you stop the search, right?
So part of this room
would be untouched.
Unless he found it in the very last
place he was looking.
Do you know the probability
of finding something
in the last possible place?
It's extremely improbable.
- I'll see you two back at the office.
- Why are you in a hurry?
Well, as much as I enjoy these
lovely surroundings, Lisbon
we have a job to do.
Am I wrong?
- Bye.
Hey, sir. What are you doing here
so late on a Friday night?
My house was burglarized.
I caught him red-handed.
Whoa. You want one of my people
to question him?
No. Sac P.D. can handle it.
It's a slam dunk.
Come Monday, when court opens
the man who broke into my house
will be very sorry that he did.
Donny Culpepper.
What a surprise to see you here.
Monday I go before a judge.
You got till then
to get me outta here.
Yeah, well, um, that could be
a little problematic.
Otherwise I will tell everyone how
you hired me to rob your boss' house.
Well, that's just snitching.
Isn't that against your...
- Code of honor?
- No.
I paid you very well
on the understanding
that you wouldn't get caught.
- Did you at least get what I wanted?
- No.
I looked everywhere.
Got into his safe. Nothing.
Just some old coins, a watch
and a Tupperware, like, tub thing.
Tupperware. Did Laroche say
anything when he found you?
He wanted to know
if I got into the safe.
- What'd you tell him?
- Nothin'.
I threw somethin' at his head and took off.
Yeah, you really blew this.
I thought you were a professional.
Don't talk down to me.
If you don't get me outta here.
By Monday, you're the one
who's gonna have to pay for it.
Trust me on that.
Trust. Yeah, really off on the good foot
with trust, are we?
- Hi.
- "Where are you?"
I thought you wanted
to get working on this case.
"I-I do. I just ran across the street"
to the, uh, fruit place
to pick up some fresh fruit.
"Flavonoids... lt's very good
for logical reasoning"
- "and visual memory, you know?"
- Very interesting. Get here quick.
Yep. I'm on my way.
The clock's running, starting now.
You close your eyes
and count to a hundred.
Thank you.
Fisher owned the repair shop
about a year and a half.
Seemed like a good citizen...
Volunteer work
with underprivileged kids
and the homeless.
Dig a little deeper.
Find out what he did before
he bought the shop.
Will do.
Hey, boss. Just talked
to Fisher's girlfriend.
She was at the morgue,
I.D.ing the body.
Kinda upset, but she agreed to meet us
at the apartment she shared with Fisher.
- All right, let's go.
- Okay.
Agent Lisbon, a word?
I just discovered that
you investigated my burglar
for a murder about a year ago...
Donny Culpepper.
- Culpepper?
- Donny Culpepper.
I remember him.
He threatened to kill me.
You're gonna have to narrow it down
a little bit more than that.
The jewelry store case.
We picked him up, found him in the hot tub.
I wonder if there's a connection.
- He's a criminal. He does wrong things.
- Yeah, probably just a coincidence then.
Yeah. Probably.
I'll let you know.
- Is there a connection?
- No.
Absolutely not.
Oh, damn. I forgot something.
Uh, I'll meet you there.
Forgot what?
My, frum baho llym or gansterning.
Miss blue?
I'm agent Lisbon.
This is agent Rigsby.
We're really sorry for your loss.
Just have a couple questions for you.
Okay. Sure.
Just a few small things.
Where were you last night?
When it happened?
Home, asleep.
I had the early shift
at the animal shelter.
Do you mind if we talk inside?
Okay.
Did your boyfriend Mr. Fisher
work that late very often?
Sometimes. If he had
a big project he had to finish.
But it's not like work
was his life or anything.
He was in balance.
Right. And, how long ago did you meet him?
About a year ago.
We met at yoga.
That's... weird.
I'm sure I locked that.
Stand back, ma'am.
Clear.
Jane was right.
Looks like somebody wanted
something Fisher had.
Call it in.
Put somebody to watch the shop.
If Jane is right, maybe
they'll go back there.
Okay, you got it.
I can't believe
this level of hostility.
There's nothing here
worth stealing.
Nothin'?
Ted and I weren't really
into material stuff.
He spent, like, eight years
in the Peace Corps.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Ma'am, can I ask you a question?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I don't mean to be intrusive.
I live upstairs.
There was a break-in here.
Did you see or hear anything?
No. A break-in?
I was at the market.
Did they steal anything?
Thank you for your time.
If you think of anything
you can give me a call at this number.
All right.
Okay. Thanks.
Sac P.D. put a man on the store.
Check on the girlfriend.
She's got no real alibi
other than being a hippie.
- Something bugging you, boss?
- Behind us. Dark late model sedan.
I'm pretty sure I saw it
outside the repair shop.
- I think it's following us.
- Got it.
And there it goes.
It's probably nothing.
Just a look-alike.
Maybe. Run the plates.
See if you find anything.
Hey.
You're new to me.
Uh, who...Who are you now?
Detention enforcement officer
O'Donnell.
Guarding the prisoner up to
and until transport.
Gung ho. Good to see.
Well, welcome, O'Donnell.
I'm Patrick Jane.
I work with the CBI.
Okay.
No worries.
Did you...Did you lose this?
A quarter.
I don't think so.
Well, it's less of a quarter
more of a good luck piece, really.
I mean, take a closer look.
Look at the way the light hits it.
Shines and gleams
like liquid sunshine.
Keep looking at it.
It's kind of soothing
the way it shines, isn't it?
You can feel your worries
and responsibilities
just... fading away.
You might even want to close your eyes
and just have a little sleep.
My Uncle had a buffalo nickel.
He was always gonna sell it
and buy a ranch and all that
but he lost it in a poker game.
So not yours, huh?
No. Maybe check upstairs.
Will do. Thank you.
I checked up on the girlfriend.
She seems clean.
No priors, committed pacifist.
People I talked to say she
and Fisher were close.
All right. Let's keep an eye on her, though.
Okay.
Hey. I pulled a message
off the victim's cell phone.
Think you wanna hear it.
"Fisher, you dog!"
"You think you can get away with this?
I find you, Fisher!"
"You're gonna pay for what you done!
You hear me, Fisher?! You pay!"
- He doesn't sound very happy.
- What's the accent?
I sent a copy down to Pete in forensics.
He can tell us.
He's a genius with accents.
What time did the call come in?
11:45 last night.
Coroner puts time of death
between 11:00 and 2:00. Bingo.
Maybe.
I'm working on getting the subscriber info
for the number from the phone
company right now.
- Good.
- Oh, boss, one more thing.
I've been looking into Fisher's past
and hit a snag with the Peace Corps thing.
What kind of snag?
Well, they've got no record of Fisher
being a member going back ten years.
I'm having them check to see
if it could be a clerical error
or spelling mistake.
Talk to the girlfriend.
Find out where he was stationed.
All right.
Are you taking a vacation
from this case or what?
Huh? No.
Boss. I put the license of the car that you
thought was following us in the system.
It was rented from the airport
three days ago.
Corporate account to some shell company
I couldn't track.
I just got a fresh hit.
The car was ticketed a half-hour ago just two
blocks away from the victim's repair shop.
Nice. Let's go.
You coming or what?
Are those bulletproof vests?
- Yeah.
- Think not.
- Good luck.
- Okay.
No light.
Locked.
Freeze!
- Drop your weapons!
- Put your hands on your heads!
Hello!
Okay. So yesterday
you were bumming change.
Here you are today
with a $1,000 handgun
nicely maintained.
You can understand
our puzzlement.
Sir, my name is Cole Ruger.
I have a license for that
and a carry permit.
Okay, Mr. Ruger
what do you know about the
death of Ted Fisher?
Nothing.
Fisher was a buddy of mine.
That's all.
You and he were
in the Peace Corps together?
No.
We worked at Sagaris together.
What is Sagaris?
A security firm.
We provide services
the regular army isn't equipped for.
Wait. You and Fisher
were mercenaries?
Private security contractors.
Where did you do
most of your contracting?
All over. Mostly Iraq.
Fallujah, Basra.
Where were you
when Fisher was killed?
Ted called me two days ago
and said he was in trouble.
He needed help.
Whatever it was
he couldn't say it over the phone.
And you just dropped everything
no questions asked, headed here?
That's right. Wouldn't you?
Where were you coming from?
I was overseas.
What did Fisher tell you
when you got here?
Nothing.
He was already dead.
I was too late.
At which point you disguised yourself
as a homeless man
to get close to the crime scene.
I was trying to gather intel,
figure out who killed Ted.
Which is why you broke into his store
with a loaded handgun?
I was staking out the place.
I heard a noise inside.
The back door was open. I went in.
I encountered that woman.
She was armed.
So I drew my weapon.
Like I said, it's fully licensed
and I have a carry permit.
Look...
Agent, I wanna work with you guys
to find out who killed Ted.
Whatever I can do. So as soon as
you cut me loose...
- Cut you loose?
- Sure.
I haven't committed a crime.
Or should I call my attorney?
Okay. Obviously, you're
not the victim's neighbor
and I need you to explain this.
My name is Vivian Griswold.
I had nothing to do with
the murder of Ted Fisher.
A client hired me six months ago
to observe Mr. Fisher.
What kind of client?
What exactly do you do?
I work for a company
providing corporate intelligence
and covert surveillance.
A private sector spy.
Who's the client?
Can't tell you that.
What I can tell you
is that it involved a major theft
from my clients, overseas
two years ago.
- And Fisher was connected how?
- He was a person of interest.
Mr. Fisher left his job shortly after
an investigation was launched.
His reasons for leaving
were... questionable.
You said you had Fisher
under surveillance.
So... where were you
the night of his death?
I had information
that led me to believe
that Mr. Fisher would be
at a different location.
- Obviously, that was bad information.
- I guess.
So... how did you come to be
in Fisher's locked shop
carrying a weapon?
I was surveilling the shop
when I heard a noise inside.
The back door was open,
and I went in.
Finding an armed man inside
I drew my fully licensed
and permitted weapon.
That's all.
Now... my lawyer is already
on the way over
but wouldn't we all rather
skip the formalities?
- You getting anything?
- Well, they're both professional liars.
Beyond that, I can't read either of them.
They're both good for the murder
so each gives the other
reasonable doubt.
We need to come at this
from another angle.
Just got off the phone
with Pete in forensics.
He says the accent's Iraqi,
probably from Baghdad.
- Any luck tracking down the caller?
- Prepaid cell phone. No subscriber info.
I tried calling it,
but the minutes must be up.
Great.
Agent Lisbon.
I just got a call from the State
Department about your case.
- What should I know?
- The State Department? What'd they say?
Our victim, Fisher, was suspected
of getting too close
to shady Iraqi businessmen.
A theft may have occurred.
Nothing could ever be proven.
They would like to be kept abreast
of developments.
We've got a threatening call
from somebody
who may or may not be Iraqi
and two suspects in holding
who've got experience
with counterintelligence.
And you have strong leads?
Something for me to tell Washington?
Nothing concrete, sir.
Early indicators say that it's revenge
for whatever happened in Iraq.
What about you, Mr. Jane?
What dazzling insights
have you gleaned?
- I've got nothing.
- That's disappointing.
- Off your game somehow? Distracted?
- No, not at all.
Sorry to interrupt, boss, but I just talked
to the girlfriend, Heather blue.
She's frightened. Says someone
is prowling around her apartment.
Let's go and see her.
I wanna ask her about
that Peace Corps thing anyway.
Jane, are you co... Damn.
- Problem?
- Not at all, sir.
- Keep me informed.
- Okay.
These people are lying to you.
Teddy was in the Peace Corps.
I told you that.
We checked.
Ted Fisher worked for Sagaris
private defense from 2000 to 2009
since he first got out of the army.
He was a mercenary.
No. He wasn't.
Not possible.
Heather, you called us here
because somebody frightened you.
Oh, well, uh...
Yeah, I was watching tv
when I heard the noise.
He was trying
to come in the back
- but when I yelled, he ran.
- Did you get a look at him?
No, I just saw the glint
of the knife he was using
to cut the screen.
You can't remember anything else
about him? Size? Hair color?
He was wearing a hooded sweatshirt, I think.
A little taller than me, maybe.
Are you sure it was male?
Could it have been a woman?
I don't know. Maybe. God, my
heart's going a mile a minute.
We've assigned you
a protection detail.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
You really want me to believe
Ted lied to me?
The whole time,
he was lying to me?
I'm sorry.
- O'Donnell. How goes it?
- Fine.
As long as they keep bringing food
every couple hours, I'm good.
Yeah. Well, I brought you a chair.
Just opens up, and...
- There.
- Great.
Yeah, it's my pleasure.
Just glad to know we got
a good man like you on the job.
Just and ease your way into it. That's...
Just ease your way down.
- Okay. There we go. Got it?
- Yeah.
Okay, fantastic. I'll check on you later on.
Okay. Thanks.
Whoever was trying
to get into the apartment
it wasn't Ruger or Griswold.
They were only released an hour ago.
Well, maybe they have somebody else
working with them
or the girlfriend is having
some very bad dreams.
Okay. Do you have any intention
of actually taking part in this case?
It's all under control.
Wait. You know who the killer is?
The what?
Oh, the killer. No. No, I misspoke.
What's going on with you?
You've been acting strange
since this case started.
Strange. Strange how?
Strange like...
Or...
Boss, Rigsby's...
Got something.
Just got a call from
the guys in evidence.
- Fisher's phone's was ringing.
- It's been going off every half-hour.
- Where did the call come from?
- Same number... Prepaid cell phone.
I thought you said the cell phone angle
was dead.
He must've put more minutes on it.
This is Cho.
Yeah, we're all set here.
How are you guys coming along?
Cho's talking to the phone company
so that when the call comes through
we can triangulate off the cell towers
figure out exactly where
the call came from.
Okay, I need you to keep him on the phone
for at least two minutes.
Hi. This is Patrick Jane.
Listen, I know who you are.
"Shut up! I am coming to get you."
"I don't know who you are,
but I will make you pay for this!"
No, you shut up. You listen to me.
I know what you want.
The only way you're gonna get it
is if you meet me in person.
We got something to settle here.
Outside the repair shop in one hour.
You be there you get what you want.
If you don't you'll never see it again.
Simple as that.
What was that?
I said 2 minutes.
That was hardly 30 seconds.
Well, I just thought it'd be simpler
to bring him to us.
It's okay. Thank me later.
Now the strangeness we were talking
about...
- Never mind.
- Okay.
Hey!
No!
Hey! Don't...
Where is that bastard Fisher? No!
Let me go!
Where is that bastard Fisher?
- Who are you?
- Come on.
- My name is Omar Hassan.
- Okay.
Why were you so angry
with Ted Fisher?
My father worked
for the Americans
helping to establish
a free and Democratic Iraq.
He and Fisher worked together.
Yes.
- Before my father was killed.
- How'd he die?
Bomb, two years ago.
Fisher was involved
in his death?
No, but when it became clear
that my father's life
was in danger
Fisher promised he would
take care of my family
if anything happened
to my father.
And Fisher told you this?
After my father was killed,
Fisher quit his job.
He...He wanted
no more of killing.
He promised to help
get us to America
and that the $2 million
would be waiting for us when we arrived.
That's a lot of money.
The State Department thinks Fisher
was engaged in criminal activity in Iraq.
Is that where the money came from?
No. It came from my father.
It was our family fortune.
Your father put a lot of trust
in Fisher.
He believed he was a good man.
He stayed under our roof.
He... He broke bread with us.
So Fisher helped to get the visas
necessary to come to America
and your family arrived four days ago.
Is that correct?
And what happened when
you met up with Fisher?
We were supposed to meet two nights ago
but he never showed up.
You thought he double-crossed you
that he stole the money
and that's why you cut the screen
and tried to break into the apartment.
Yes.
What about Fisher's friend,
Cole Ruger?
Did you ever meet him or did Fisher
ever talk about him?
No, I-I don't know him.
What am I to tell my mother?
My sisters?
I mean, we have nothing now.
Yeah. It's a tough break.
I'll be right back.
The kid doesn't seem
like a killer.
I'm not sure the revenge
motive works.
- What are you doing? What is that?
- None of your business.
Are you even listening to me?
Every word.
Let's go catch this killer, shall we?
How are we gonna do that?
The killer was looking for the Hassan
family's $2 million. The rest is easy.
And now you want me to ask you
what the plan you worked out is don't you?
No. I just want you to round everyone up
and get 'em to the repair shop.
- Everyone? Who's everyone?
- Well, let me see.
There's the girlfriend and Omar there
and, Griswold and Ruger.
- I think that about covers it.
- Ruger and Griswold...
They've already been released.
And from what I've seen of the two of them
we're not really equipped to track 'em down.
Oh, no. It's gonna be easy.
Easy? Ruger bought a plane ticket
out of the country...
The second he left the CBI.
Griswold disappeared
even after we put a tail on her.
Ruger is not leaving the country.
He is after the money.
You heard Omar.
He'd never even heard of Ruger.
Ruger worked with Fisher, but I bet
they weren't friends.
- And Griswold?
- Well, she's after the money, too.
I expect they're both trying to get into
the repair shop as we speak.
You just have to round them up.
Call me if you need any help.
Wait a minute.
You're leaving again?
What is going on with you?
When have I ever
steered you wrong before?
I mean, when have I ever
really steered you wrong
where I've done something
that didn't work out
- the way we wanted it to?
- Seriously?
Okay, fine. Let me put it this way...
When have I ever intentionally
screwed things up
so that we couldn't solve the case?
No. Not that I know of, at least.
That's right. Thank you.
Have a little faith, Lisbon.
Okay, Jane said
they're here somewhere.
Let's take a look.
- Probably not the homeless guy.
- No, Ruger tried that one before.
How about the food guys?
No, too short.
Gotta be the truck?
- That's it.
- Yep.
- Hey, guys, I got this.
- Yes, you do.
Hello Mr. Ruger.
- How you're doing?
- What do you want?
I'm not breaking any laws.
We just wanted to ask you
into the repair shop.
It would be a big help for us.
All right. No problem.
One down, one to go.
- See anything?
- Nope.
- "Cho, how's it going?"
- "We found Ruger in a delivery van"
- "but Griswold's nowhere in sight."
- Are you near the repair shop?
Yeah, right out front.
Okay, from where you stand
what is the best vantage point
to see the shop?
He wants us to look for the best observation
post for watching the shop.
How about way over there?
That building right across the street?
There's a building across the street.
Rooftop's good.
Do you have a pen and some paper?
What's up?
What are you doing?
Throw me a pen.
- A pen?
- Yeah.
Nice catch.
Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
Hey, O'Donnell, snack break.
- Oh, thanks, buddy.
- No problem.
It's about time.
Turkey.
Look, you gotta put this on.
We don't have a lot of time.
You're gonna use this
to get out through the door.
- Wait. What are you talking about?
- Well, you asked me to get you out of here.
That's what I'm doing...Helping you escape.
Now hurry up.
Escape? I'm not escaping.
You think I want to spend
the rest of my life on the run?
No. You get the charges dropped.
That's the deal.
Hey, whoa, whoa.
I'm not a lawyer.
I can't make charges
just disappear
but I can get you to Mexico...
Set you up with a little starter money.
Mexico? Who the hell wants
to go to Mexico?
You get me out free and legal,
or I start talking.
I'm pretty sure the dirt I got on you
will be worth
a "get out of jail free" card.
You're very annoying.
And you're running out of time.
Are they the ones?
Are you going to arrest them?
Oh, hi. You must be Heather.
Thanks for coming by.
Ted Fisher was a good man
who kept trust
with the Hassan family.
He was murdered over $2 million,
which is somewhere in this room.
$2 million?
Ted didn't have $2 million.
Uh, yes he did.
They could tell you.
How do you know it's in this room?
Because we've checked every other location
connected to Fisher and so have you.
That's why you're here.
Hasn't this room already been searched
both by the killer and by the police?
Yes, but they...I'm sorry...
Weren't creative enough.
It could be in bearer bonds
hidden in the bills
or invoices or files
or more likely,
in the form of jewels
hidden somewhere inside
these electronics.
Whatever form it's in,
we're gonna find it right now.
Come on in, folks.
These people are gonna take everything
and pull it apart
until they find the hidden treasure.
Yes, piece by piece
until we find it.
Thank you, folks.
If everybody could just step outside
and let these people do their jobs.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
They didn't find anything.
No cash, no jewels,
no bonds. Nothin'.
What am I going to do?
My family is ruined.
All my father did
was for nothing.
What a waste of time.
I'd agree with him, except
it's this kind of incompetence
that makes people pay me
to produce results.
These people have all been lying to you.
I was right about Teddy.
You were wrong.
I figured it out.
I know exactly
where the fortune is.
Where is it then?
Where's the money?
You're on top of it.
Under the carpet?
No. It is the carpet.
Touch it.
Pure silk, hand-knotted.
It looks like
a dirty old carpet.
Oh, yes, it's very old.
One of the reasons it's so valuable.
- I gotta phone this in.
- Stop.
Let's talk about this.
If you did call it in the legal mess
will take forever to sort out.
This carpet will just end up in
a government locker somewhere.
Yeah, probably.
What if we just...
Took it?
You and me?
We took the carpet
sold it, and divided
the profits between us?
Exactly.
That's, uh...
That's a great idea.
- Isn't it?
- 50/50 split?
- Sure. 50/50.
- Deal.
Deal.
What did Ted say when you
suggested that deal to him?
Ted was a softheaded fool.
So you knew about the money.
You knew Ted wasn't
with the Peace Corps.
- You knew everything.
- I didn't...I didn't say that.
Oh, yes you did which means, Heather,
it was you that shot Ted.
He told you about his identity,
he told you about the money
- and you shot him for it.
- No. Uh, that's...No!
Well, forgive me if I...
I'm not quite convinced.
But I do have to phone this in.
- Lisbon'll be very happy to know...
- Stop.
Are you pointing a gun at me,
Heather?
The man I loved was
in the Peace Corps.
He wanted to make the world
a better place.
Ted wasn't who he said he was.
He was a soldier, a killer.
So you shot him?
That's a little counterintuitive.
He lied to me!
This had nothing to do
with the $2 million?
You can't understand.
You can only see things from
your bourgeois capitalist mindset.
Do you know how much good
could be done with $2 million?!
How many animals could be saved?!
But you couldn't find the money.
The clock was ticking.
You looked everywhere,
and you couldn't find it.
He caught me
searching the shop.
He talked to me like
I was some kind of criminal.
Well, uh, pretty much what you are.
No. I'm blessed is what I am.
The universe wants me
to have this money.
I'm sorry, I have to kill you
but I'm doing it from a place of love.
Drop the gun.
Put your hands on your head.
Oh, wow.
I'm gonna leave you with that.
You were right about Ruger
and Griswold.
He's already disappeared
and she's admitted she was working
for the State Department
who suspected Fisher
of smuggling and theft.
But they've agreed to recognize
the Hassan family's right to the rug
so everything ends happily.
Good.
I waited for you to tell the Hassans.
Come on.
Oh, no, thanks.
- What do you mean, "no, thanks"?
- Well, uh, you know
I don't have time
for that kind of treacle.
I have to rearrange
my sock drawer.
I have a serious problem
I have to solve
and I don't have a lot of time
to solve it in.
I knew something
was going on with you.
What is it?
The absolute truth,
or I beat it outta you.
Laroche has something I need,
so I hired Culpepper
to break into Laroche's house.
If I can't get the charges dropped
Culpepper is gonna tell on me.
Oh... my God.
Yeah, it's not good.
What does Laroche have
that you want?
Hightower didn't murder anybody.
She was framed.
Red John has a friend inside the CBI.
The Todd Johnson murder.
Laroche had a short list of suspects
that led to Hightower.
That's what you were
trying to steal...The list.
Yes. There were four names
on that list besides Hightower's.
- One of them is working for red John.
- Did you ask Laroche?
Laroche? No. Because if
it's not one of those names
then Laroche is Red John's man.
Why didn't you tell me about this earlier?
I don't want to put you in danger.
You're an idiot.
I will fix this but we are gonna have
a serious talk after.
Fix it?
I've been trying to fix it all weekend.
I had the perfect escape worked out
and then Culpepper says,
"no, I want the charges dropped"
Yeah, yeah. Let's go.
Open it up.
- He's in there with his lawyer.
- Perfect.
Lady cop. Okay. I can get behind that.
A dumb cop who's pretty
is better than a dumb cop who ain't...
What do you think you're doing here?!
You...You can't do that.
That's a violation of due process.
You just got this case dismissed.
"What were you thinking Agent Lisbon?"
Due to your actions,
a criminal is going free.
I'm sorry, sir.
The frustrations of the job...
Your apologies
are of no import, agent.
Donald Culpepper can no longer
be brought to trial.
Well, hang on.
He didn't actually steal anything, did he?
The 1-week suspension is mandatory.
Also, six months
of anger management classes.
Yes, sir.
- I thought that went well.
- You're gonna owe me big-time.
- Uh, for what exactly?
- Or I will...
Two words...
Anger management.
Hey.
Thank you.